Isaac Chavez

Houston, Texas 77095 | 281-935-5556 | isaac-chavez.com | isaacgc0596@gmail.com | Github | Medium | Linkedin

Full-stack Software Engineer

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming and the implementation of Object-oriented programming. Self-motivated and possession of strong skills in critical thinking/problem solving, with an interest in how things work in unison, that helps when working with both server side and client-side languages, allowing myself to gain a better understanding and to experiment with different methods/solutions to solve complex problems. Skills to see the big picture in terms of people, places, and needs, without compromising small details when working in a fast-paced environment, as well as collaborate/communicate well with others as a team to meet deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJs, Python

Frameworks/Database: Rails, Express, React, Redux, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, JSON, SQL, MongoDB, UI Frameworks **Methodologies:** Object-oriented programming(OOP), Test-Driven Development, REST Apis, MVC, DRY, Scrum/Agile, Testing/Debugging, NPM, Git, Browser developer tools, Structure, Exterior design, Autocomplete, Scripting language

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Chatter - Github MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJS (M.E.R.N) Material UI

Users are able to search and join/leave rooms, create rooms, view members, send/edit/delete messages

- Used <u>socket.io</u> for real time, for all changes across all users(c.r.u.d messages, online activity, leave/join rooms)
- See visibly of user when they are online & when they log off to signal other users who are online & login/signup auth
- Be able to edit messages and delete messages from only the current user who deleted it
- Implementation of react hooks for proficiency and quicker rendering

Take A Trip - Github | Demo Ruby, Rails, ReactJs, Redux, TripadviserApi, WeatherApi, Ant and Material UI Users are able to plan trips out by searching for various things to do around their location, and may also add other users to join in on the trip to plan out more ideas

- Used Redux as a way to save state and to be accessible across different pages of the app allowing less conflict and creating a single source of truth
- Used different APIs to be able to gather data from various locations to make a more dynamic website, as well as an API to gather data on the weather for the user's location
- Able to utilize frameworks to style/design the frontend and give more functionality towards the website
- Used only functional components to be able to better understand hooks and being able to implement them

Shoptastic - Github | Demo Ruby, Rails, ReactJs, TargetApi, GoogleApi, React Bootstrap, Semantic UI E-commerce website where users can search by categories for various items and be able to purchase them, edit their cart and view store locations

- Used an API to gather different sets of products based on a users choice making it more dynamic
- Able to use Google Maps API to lookup store locations as well as a users input for locations in their area
- Used a React Bootstrap and Semantic Ui frameworks to design website
- Create different route pages for a more dynamic website

EXPERIENCE

Watson Grinding & Manufacturing

Abrasive Blaster/HVOF Operator

Houston, Texas 03/2017 - 02/2020

- Maximizing workflow and production by preparing parts by masking and blasting so that it may be ready to be applied with a coating
- Set up parts and write programs for which the robot may complete by recording sizes and dimensions, apply carbide
 coating, make sure gun is running smoothly by adjusting gas levels and repairing the gun parts for better
 performance, prolonging the life of hardware therefore saving and reducing company cost
- Good troubleshooting skills, ability to multitask, and good time management, consequently improving manufacturing

Landscaping | Polo

Horticulturalist

Houston, Texas 06/2016 - 03/2017

- Operated all power equipment such as mowers, weed eaters, etc. to optimize time and increase efficiency
- Laying down mulch, build and stain fences to accommodate client needs
- Satisfy client preferences by preserving a comprehensive outlook while being able to pay attention to details
- Great teamwork skills to accomplish tasks on time, therefore increasing productivity and minimize time/money

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Software Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
Maybe Creek HighSchool
High School Diploma

Houston, Texas 03/ 2020 - 06/2020 Houston, Texas 06/ 2016